# Nickson Kaigi | Curriculum Vitae

6677-00100, Nairobi Kenya

☐ +254 724 708 852

• ☑ nickaigi@gmail.com

• http://nickaigi.github.io/

Software engineer, with expansive knowledge of Python and JavaScript. Driven individual, with a background in Computer Science and vast experience developing and shipping software and data products. Currently pursuing a Master's of Science Degree in Computation Intelligence at The University of Nairobi.

# **Experience**

#### Sum Software Limited

Full Stack Engineer

November 2021 - July 2022

Was an engineer working on the Sumfully software. Sumfully is a Amazon Profit Analytics and Inventory Management Tool.

#### World Bank

Technical Consultant

December 2021 - January 2022

Working with The Data and Evidence for Justice Reform (DE JURE) and Development Impact Evaluation (DIME) units in the development of data-driven applications with the intention of studying, improving efficiency, quality and access to justice in developing countries.

#### Maxum Data

Lead Developer

June 2015 - October 2021

Lead developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration. I was responsible for design and development of the in-house analysis and reporting tool. I wrote Lua scripts that acted as an interface to a custom installation of Freeswitch. I wrote bash scripts that would analyse the production databases for changes that met a predetermined threshold, resulting in a call to action when the changes met the threshold. Wrote Python scripts that analysed spending on toll free and regular phone numbers and created monthly billing reports.

#### **Domains Bot**

Senior Python Developer

*June 2015 – September 2015* 

Senior developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration.

### SunUp Financial LLC (Balance Credit)

Senior Python Developer

May 2014 – January 2015

Senior developer in charge of back end development, server setup and maintenance on AWS, Django templating, Nginx and uWSGI configuration.

Soko Nairobi

Senior Python Developer

July 2013 - April 2014

Senior developer in charge of UX, Python and Android development for the suite of open source and enterprise tools that the company provided.

#### **Sweet Relish**

Senior Python Developer

December 2012 - July 2013

Python developer working with Django and jQuery mobile to deliver a mobile friendly version of the website.

#### **Code Painters**

Lead Software Developer

September – November 2012

Lead developer responsible for product development of various Python Django based web applications.

#### **Apartment Rentals**

Software Developer

April 2012

Python Django developer responsible for providing end-to-end Programming support.

#### MANteresting

Python/ Django Developer

March - April 2012

Python Django developer responsible for design and implementation of a REST based API.

#### Alliance Technologies

Nairobi

Software Engineer (intern)

September – December 2011

Engineering intern responsible for extending the A1ERP data dictionary and developing an android based prototype of the ERP.

# **Education**

#### Academic Qualifications

University of Nairobi

Nairobi, Kenya

MSc Computation Intelligence, Completed Coursework. Thesis in Progress

2014-Present

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Nairobi, Kenya

BSc Computer Science, Second Class Honors, Upper Division

2008-2012

Menengai High School

Nakuru, Kenya

KCSE

2003-2006

# **Technical and Personal skills**

• **Programming Languages:** Proficient in: Python, JavaScript, TEX Also basic ability with: C/C++.

# Interests and extra-curricular activity

- I enjoy the game of Chess
- O I am an avid reader of fiction, high fantasy, biographical, and historical/historical fiction books

## References

Up to 3 references available on request